KristijanPerusko

software engineer

Contact

kristijan.perusko@yahoo.com

Links

Linkedin:// kperusko Github:// kperusko Bitbucket:// kperusko

Languages

English, Croatian

Programming

PHP, JavaScript CSS & HTML

Some experience: Java, Python C# (Silverlight), VB.Net Scala, Racket, Octave

Db

MongoDB, MySQL

Os

Ubuntu, Debian Fedora, CentOS Windows

Other

Git, Mercurial, SVN Apache2, RabbitMQ AWS, S3, Heroku

Summary

I'm interested in databases and functional programming. I'm passionate about learning and solving hard problems. I worked as a full stack and back-end software engineer, but I prefer working with algorithms, databases, implementing APIs and doing system-wide optimizations.

Experience

2008-2014 **Novatec**Worked on in-house projects for two years as a software engineer. Became a team lead to build a booking system and multiple customer facing sites. I had several roles

lead to build a booking system and multiple customer facing sites. I had several roles in my team including being project/team lead, admininistration and optimization of

MongoDB and MySQL DBs, provisioning of Debian servers.

2007-2008 **Tempo** IT administrator

Principal responsibility in several areas including Windows administration and user support, configuration and management of infrastructure and equipment in 8 remote offices. Managed system upgrade for compliance with EU customs legislation.

2005-2007 **Vlado elektronika** Sofware and electrical QA engineer

Created hardware testbed and software for computer aided testing of intrusion alarm system. This system automated 90% of the tests and lowered the testing time for each

ooard by 60%.

Education

since 2013	BS of information tehnology	Veleuciliste u Rijeci
	Silverlight 5 and MS Sync Framework	
since 2002	Electrical engineering	Mate Blazina high school
	DC servo driver controlled by IR remote	

Certifications

07 2014	M202: MongoDB Advanced Deployment and Operations <i>MongoDB</i>	MongoDB
11 2013	Principles of Reactive Programming <i>École Polytechnique Fédérale de Lausanne</i>	Coursera
10 2013	Machine Learning Stanford University	Coursera
10 2013	Interactive Programming in Python Rice University	Coursera
10 2013	M101JS MongoDB for Node.js Developers <i>MongoDB</i>	MongoDB
09 2013	Functional Programming Principles in Scala Ecole Polytechnique Federale de Lausanne	Coursera
06 2013	Startup Engineering Stanford University	Coursera